## **Emory Mears**

### she/her emory@uml.cafe (203)-913-9891 https://github.com/nemears

An imaginative software engineer with determination to deliver well thought out honest work that is modern and fast. Well rounded with experience, determined to provide insight to create efficient and functional code to get the job done.

### Skills

C++, C, Rust, Java, Python, POSIX, Bash, Typescript, Javascript, Modeling and Simulation, UML/SysML, Cmake, Gradle, Groovy, Kotlin, DIS, Modern C++ Design, Networking and Sockets, Systems Programming, Concurrent Programming

### Experience

# Software Systems Engineer at MITRE MITRE, 202 Burlington Rd, Bedford MA October 2019 - Current

Software Systems Engineer for the Emerging Systems Engineering Technologies department at MITRE. MITRE assigns staff to work on two seperate projects at a time, so resonsibilities and tasking varied based on what what was assigned. The following is the description of the projects and tasks that she completed, most recent to least. Most recently she worked on C++ model of a system to be used for testing, mostly working on the routing of data throughout it so it could integrate well. She also worked on a set of tools used for identifying important connections in models of networks. Another effort she worked on was integrating a simulation environment with the modeling tool MagicDraw, this involved a set of static analysis tools that looked at the Abstract Syntax Tree of the simulation's code and populating diagrams and tables within the modeling software. The first project she did at MITRE was a tool using proxmox the virtualization manager to spin up qemu virtual machines and set up a network based on configuration files supplied. The program would then run MITRE's caldera ("red team" hacker bot) on the virtualized network and machines.

#### uml.cafe Independent, June 2021 - Current

uml.cafe is the domain name of a live, multi-user, UML diagramming web application made completely by Emory. It is compromised of 4 different code repositories that she worked on in her free time after work. The four parts are: The simple and quick uml-cpp which manages the core of the uml operations on the backend per user. uml-user-service is a websocket server written in Rust used as a layer to handle user level interactions and serves as the website api endpoint. uml-js is the Javascript library that serves as the api to interact with the backend / endpoint of the server. open-uml2 is the Vue frontend app that makes up the visuals of uml.cafe. Play around with it if you have time.

### Non-Equilibrium Thermodynamics Research WPI, June 2018 - June 2019

While working on the WPI senior year MQP capstone she was able to work in a lab and assisted with some image analysis algorithms written in python that were used and eventually cited in a publication in Nature.

### Education

Worcester Polytechnic Institute: Bachelors of Science in Physics with a minor in Computer Science GPA: 3.75 Graduated May 2019 with High Distinction